Hi there I'm Melody Mooney and I'm going to share with you some tips on how to fold your clothes.
Today we're going to fold a dress shirt, but first things first.
I always start out with a flat surface.
So, get yourself a flat surface.
It can be your kitchen table or your bed or the floor, but get on a flat surface.
First thing I do is I get myself a one by one piece of cardboard for my folding.
Now, I'll show you what to do with that in a minute.
Next thing is I shake out my shirt.
I want to make sure all the buttons are done up.
This is a good time to check and make sure the shirt indeed has all its buttons and this one does.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to put the front side flat down on my area with the sleeves lying flat out.
So, now I'm looking at the back of the shirt, making it smooth.
I take my one by one cardboard.
I put it right in the shoulders where there's a gather.
Start with my left side.
I'm going to fold in, take my collar, grab it, fold this into the center and fold it one time back towards the left, so it looks like that.
So, I'll show you it again on the right side.
Here we go.
Take my right side at the cuff; fold it into the middle and then one time back towards the right.
So, they're matching there.
I have two sides going right down here.
I've made a fold.
Now, what I want to do is I want to take the bottom and I'm going to fold this up.
I'm moving the cardboard up.
Fold this bottom up to the center, like so.
Now, I'm going to slide out my cardboard piece, put it to the side.
All that's left to do is fold one more time.
Look at that.
Great, flat folded.
If you're traveling or you need to store them everything is neat and flat.
There you have it; how to fold a dress shirt.